+92-331-5250039

BABAR ALI KHAN

babaralikhan@rocketmail.com

House#B-68, Main Boulevard, New City, Phase-2

Wah Cantt, 47040



SUMMARY

Knowledgeable NOC Engineer with entry level experience in network monitoring, routing, switching and troubleshooting. Highly- trained and proficient in working independently to assess test and remedy network issues. Experienced in troubleticketing, documentation and technical support equipped with strong communication and analytical skills.



WORK EXPERIENCE

Five-by-Five Communication Islamabad

NOC Engineer

July 2017-Present

- •Responsible for Configuration of VOIP based voice traffic over International routes using MBX3000 Softswitch.
- •Mantaining good traffic stats by consistent monitoring the network quality factors and analyzing traffic profiles.
- •Creating the best traffic forwarding plans using Least Cost Routings (LCR) and ASR/ACD based.
- •Interconnecting with global VOIP suppliers and customers with technical terms.
- •Initiating the testings on global traffic routes for network quality assurance.
- •Analyzing and Generating Daily traffic reports using Microsoft Excel.
- •Providing technical assistance and coordination; facilitating efforts with multiple support organizations internally, service providers, vendors and any other outside support organizations as needed.
- •Initiating, updating, tracking and closing trouble tickets; creating and sending network alerts as needed to internal organizations as well as Vendors.

PTCL

Islamabad

Management Associate

July 2016-June 2017

- •Researched and recommended network and data communications between hardware and
- •Analyzed user-generated trouble tickets and provided technical support using MM&BB Portal.
- •Provided customer database upgradation using Seibel CRM 8.1.
- •Performed telecommunication and networking business evaluations.
- •Generated daily/weekly reports regarding business targets, achievements, customers track record, and proposals using Microsoft Excel.
- •Coordinated and sucessfully accomplished regional infrastructure and development analysis projects.



INTERNSHIP

JAZZ

Islamabad

Internee Engineer
March 2016-June 2016

- •Worked closely with network administrators and server engineers to ensure quality service.
- •Performed Drive Testing for the network performance evaluation using NEMO OUTDOOR.
- •Analyzed and interpreted complex data from multiple sources using NEMO ANALYZE



EDUCATION

BS Electrical Engineering

Majors: Telecommunications

COMSATS Institute of Information Technology

Islamabad

software.

February 2012 - February 2016

Intermediate

Majors: Pre-Engineering

F.G Degree College for Men

Wah Cantt

September 2009 - August 2011

Matric

Majors: Science

Wah Islamic School of Excellence

Wah Cantt

March 2007 - June 2009



Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA)

Routing & Switching

Huawei Certified Network Associate (HCNA)

Routing & Switching

Corvit Systems

Rawalpindi October 2017

Corvit Systems

Rawalpindi January 2018



AWARDS

Prime Minister National ICT Scholarship Award (IGNITE)

Feb 2012 - Feb 2016



SKILLS

- .Voice Over IP (VoIP)
- .Network Support
- .Network Operations
- .Team Work
- .Technical Writing
- .Diversification



HOBBIES

- .Cricket
- .Badminton
- .Designing
- .Music
- .Traveling